Ramesh Ojha

Having 4 years of experience in programming (mostly in frontend), and I am looking for a good opportunity where I can enhance my core skills. I also have an engineering degree and have good knowledge of computer science and information technologies. Currently pursuing master's course from online distance education.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Coforge Limited

Dec 2023 - Present

- Worked on complicated screens development with approximately 10-15 API calls on single page.
- Did R&D, POC and implementation of Dark Mode from scratch.
- Followed test driven development approach for repo migration.
- Wrote unit test cases for old legacy project where increased code coverage from 35% to approximately 80%.
- Worked on technologies like NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Axios, MUI, Storybook, Jest (RTL), HTML, SCSS, GIT and AWS.

Solution Engineer, Degode

Jun 2021 - Dec 2023

- Did R&D, POC and implementation of whitelabeling in the legacy project based on automated chat-support application.
- Debugged production level bugs and resolved it in quick time.
- Created atomic and molecular components for UI in ReactJS.
- Have implemented servers and connected it to database.
- Worked on TypeScript, NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, ExpressJS, MongoDB, GrapghQL, Socket.io, GIT, Jenkins and AWS.

Project Intern, Sudhya Developer Core

Dec 2020 - March 2021

- Got exposure to full stack web app development (e-commerce application)
- Participated in creating CRUD operation code on server.
- · Did code reading and code cleanup.
- Technology used ReactJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, TypeORM, NodeJS.

Educational Background

Master of Computer Application (MCA) (Pursuing Currently)

Indra Gandhi National Open University

Jan 2023 - Present

· Learning DSA, ML, AI, Python and System Design.

Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering

Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam Technical University Aug 2013 - Jul 2018

• Got exposure to C, C++, HTML and CSS.

Contact

Noida Sector 59 +91-9540205885 +91-9205018942 ramstartwork@gmail.com www.rameshojha.com Leetcode - rameshojha3131 freecodecamp.org/rameshojha github.com/RameshOj

Skills

Frontend Skills

- · NextJS, ReactJS, Redux
- HTML, CSS, SCSS
- · JavaScript, TypeScript
- JQery, MUI

Backend Skills

- ExpressJS
- MongoDB, TypeORM
- Python

Additional Skills

- · Jenkins, Vercel, ArgoCD
- · Jest, RTL, Enzyme
- · Python, Docker
- Socket.io, Open Al API's
- AWS S3, EC2, Elastic Beanstalk

Certification/Short Courses

- Responsive Web Designing
- Javascript Algorithm & Data Structure
- Frontend Development Libraries
- NextJs
- Advanced React & Storybook

Additional Information

- Managing 2-3 Junior Developers in my current project.
- Participate in extra curricular activites and campus sports competition.